welcome everyone
in the manifest wasabi research club
today we are reviewing a fresh paper
a new paper that's so new that
i believe it's only a prep print at this
point
bitcoin privacy a survey on
mixing techniques and this is
a metal analysis of
almost all the bitcoin privacy
techniques i can
think of even things that i wasn't aware
of
before so this is a really interesting
paper and we have today the author
simin kashmati and a co-author
say hi shimmy
yes hi everyone i'm simion lasmati
and as adam told currently i'm working
on blockchain privacy
especially for bitcoin privacy and i'm
working in
sba research and i'm a phd student in
vienna university of technology
all right and could you talk a bit about
the contributions of the paper there are
multiple authors walid
and edgar may right
uh yes actually a valid uh is my mentor
our team leading sp research and edgar
wifer is my supervisor
oh i see oh i see so so this is
this is almost your brainchild
or mostly that's that's good
yes all right so
how should we how should start it
i have to propose one
could be someone
gives an overview of the paper
or i would ask si simeone to
to talk about the history uh
how did you you get here
uh and and what went through your mind
to start
examining this topic
can anyone give an overview would anyone
like to give an overview
i would actually like to hear simeon
give the overview
all right
so ask me
can you talk about the paper and it
would be interesting to
to go from historical perspective that
how
you cut in to to bitcoin privacy
um and
how did you put the things together
because this is a lot of things right it
looks like
you have to go through many many papers
uh yeah actually i can also
walk through over the paper i can also
just provide some information about the
paper
and then we can discuss about the
results
whatever you prefer
uh please then give an overview of the
paper
okay can i share the screen
um afraid you can't
you can try but last time i checked gt
didn't work
for screen sharing
see if you're on the desktop it should
be the
third button from the left on the bottom
of the screen
yep oh it's good it's good
okay so
you can see the paper right yes
yep all right i should fold this paper
uh
the story was uh started from
participating
in a course in vienna university of
technology
which was about the data science uh
on cryptocurrencies and in that course
we have uh
some projects in uh the anonymization of
uh bitcoin actually and then from
that of course i i got uh
some insights about the privacy problems
uh in the um cryptocurrencies and
blockchain and also the proposed
solutions
to mediate them back then
i decided to work on these
techniques actually and uh when
i went through the techniques
i just found some um
prominent techniques such as corn join
and
uh at that time mixing websites for
instance
and when i continued our
my research i found that there are lots
of
proposals in this area and
it's they are not just one or two
techniques then after that
i decided uh to do
a survey
to provide most of the techniques and
then
compare them over some criteria
the main research questions was uh
the main research questions actually
were
to find and compare those techniques
over
privacy security and efficiency criteria
which i adopted from the literature
and for actually this paper
changed a lot during past two years
uh i started at in 2019 and then
uh i found even some of my
categorizations
were wrong and then i updated in the
paper
for the paper apart from background and
fundamentals
every one should be known before
going to mixing techniques
we provided the definitions for the
transactions and
the different type of transactions such
as a time lock transactions hash lock
transactions
and htocs and then we provided uh
what what's the what is the problem uh
and the problem with the anonymization
attacks and
the research that uh proposed
some heuristics and and
the most commonly used one was common
input ownership heuristic
and most of the technique mixing
techniques
uh try to overcome these
fundamental heuristic to prevent
any actually the
the anonymization attack and uh
when i found those mixing techniques
first i tried to categorize them as
centralized and decentralized techniques
and then i found that it's not a correct
categorizations
as uh although for instance for
coin join uh in
transaction level the conjoint is
decentralized
however in the network level it's
centralized
when you have to contact a coordinator
or
when the participants have to
find each other in a bulletin board so i
decided to find a better categorization
for these mixing techniques as of now
i categorized them in
four main categories
the first one is centralized mixers
which was
the techniques that are based on
uh mixing websites and uh
we in the literature we had mixed coin
and then blind coin and then like mix
in mixing website all the users actually
forward the coins to a centralized
mixers and then
the mixer mix the coins and shuffle the
output addresses and send
the coins to the destination addresses
mixedcoin
provided uh some sort of
warranty from a mixer to be sure that
if the mixer cheated their
users can publicize their warranties
although it provides some sort of
accountability but it can
provide depth resistance actually
and then blind coin uh proposed blind
signature for mixed coin and then like
mix
proposed uh using multi signatures with
mixer
to blind coin to actually
make it better and we also have obscure
which use a trusted
[Music]
environment for centralized mixer
apart from this uh we have conjoined
based
uh techniques uh which was proposed by
maxwell
and back then corn shuffle coin shuffle
plus plus
and value shuffle by tim buffing and
uh and also conjoined xt
which is chaining the transactions uh
using coinjoin by adam gibson and also a
sneaker
which is an interactive unattractive
actually
a coin join and pay join
which was uh first uh proposed by black
student
under the name pay to end point and then
pay join actually adopted by most of the
wallets and in the community and for uh
atonic swept uh i uh
i put fader exchange uh protocols in
this category fair exchange
and zim which also use fader exchange
but
it proposes a new technique to find
another party uh by
advertising on the blockchain and then
we have coin swap
which proposed by maxwell but at that
time we didn't have a
check like time verify and segment and
then
new coin swap which i read that in
adam vipson's weblog which uses
a segwit and also um
check lifetime verify for the
blockchain transaction and we also have
pay sub which was recently
proposed by chris belser to
actually to use
construct new coin swap design and also
combine it with page on which provide
better privacy
and we for off chain and
unchain transactions we have blindly
signed contract
and also tumbleweed but by ethan hilman
and for threshold signatures these
papers
are those that i found
through my research and actually
uh all the threshold signatures that we
can
use in bitcoin which are
which can be used in ecdsas scheme can
be used
for mixing but these three
are those papers that i found them in
coin parties that you
and secure escrow address
and then the paper just provide a
short description about these techniques
and
here in discussion and evaluation
we compare them over
these privacy security and efficiency
criteria can i continue
or is there any question
so just an idea that i believe the best
way would be to go through
your categories one by one and
and and everyone can share their
thoughts on the things
that actually make sense uh but
please continue after on let's proceed
like this
and here in the table
we try to provide
those criterias and compare the
techniques
uh by providing if they
have full coverage of this criterion
actually
or partial coverage or no coverage
and at the end uh and for
privacy uh we did we
compare them over anonymity set on
linkability and on traceability based on
crypto node
definition and also value privacy
and for security we adopted
depth resistance dust resistant and
civil resistance
and for efficiency we compare them if
they
need to interact with input users
if they need to interact with the
recipient
if the technique is compatible with
bitcoin
and if the technique provide directly
sending to the desired destination
address
and we also provided the number of
transactions
and also the minimum block for one mixra
and these uh last um two last columns
actually
provide uh the delays and the fees
uh some insights actually about the fees
and delays uh that
most of them does these techniques
need
so
um
all right thank you for the great
overview of the paper
um let's dive into the next section
which is going through all the
categories that
that you identified and before that i
would just like to ask if anyone would
hotel thinks that there is category may
be missing or
or or would make any changes the four
categories are atomic swap
coin join base centralized mixers and
threshold signatures
so any disagreement so far
all right it looks like uh everyone
agrees on the
basic categories and now let's continue
with
the thing that i know the least about
which are the threshold signature
schemes
coin party i know nothing much
uh thinks very highly about coin party
secure coin i don't really know
anything about that and sea
uh that sounds familiar to me too so
um guys any interesting insights
here
maybe nothing much you can talk about
your love of
coin party uh
well to be clear what i like about coin
party is
the on-chain footprint uh the
coordination protocol is
uh not so much my favorite because uh
it relies on these like semi-trusted uh
parties it's essentially
a federation unless you identify the
the mixing peers with the users if if
that's the same group of entities
then it's a uh i guess you could say
it's
kind of like uh similar to
coinjoin xt in a way i don't know it's
hard to say
but it's um yeah what i like about coin
party
is that it's um
it leaves an on-chain footprint that
looks a lot like coin swap
uh but it's it's more like a a
multi-party
mixing transaction so
um from a more like uh i guess economic
point of view it's a little bit more
like coin join
so i'm like the reason i find it
interesting is kind of
um you could do
more interesting coin join like
protocols
in the future with the same like
on-chain techniques
that's why i think it's cool
all right any other insights on
threshold signature based schemes
or can we move on
to atomic swaps
all right so far exchange and
theme i believe siem was
the scheme that was advertising itself
with severe resistance right
oh yes by paying a
a coin to miner to advertise
actually you're willingless for mixing
it makes it expensive right that's the
idea
yes and by the way
that actually happens in coinjoin
that's one thing i was noting when i was
reading
back in the day the zinc paper
anyhow coin spot
new coin swap and face lock
this is a very hot topic today so
as you explained coin swap was
proposed by maxwell new coins fought
by adam gibson and
chris batcher is proposed and
implementing baseball
is that correct he's working on the
implementation
yeah it's a rust-based implementation
of the routed um like patrons
sorry coin swap stuff with um i believe
the
multi-party cdsa stuff is not yet
implemented but
um with like normal scripts uh it
already had
testnet transactions if i'm not mistaken
[Music]
all right so that's coming along and
there is bsc and tumblit
tumblebit is something i'm intimately
familiar with because i spent a few
years
working on it uh bsc
is is that a scientific paper that ethan
hermann
uh wrote also like number bit
yes exactly right and they use blind
signature
and back then as it was not compatible
with bitcoin blockchain
they proposed tumbleweed and
[Music]
i guess the top of it is the better
version
for doing the payment channel
and but uh honestly speaking
uh i couldn't find any better version
implementation of
these atomic swap
proposals although breeze wallet and end
humble withdrawal
were on github but
they are not are they're
uh commercial wallet or
how to say that better version
yes so so so what happened here is that
i was working on bitcoin privacy at the
time uh
joining market trying to build a joint
market while at hand
nicoladori who wrote the
c-sharp bitcoin library told me that
he's going to also work on bitcoin
privacy but
not on coinjoin but on this new thing
called
tamba bit and
and then that was a clear
sign for me that i have to work on that
too because nicolas is going to do that
and
that's how ann tumbled it uh was born
and in the beginning when antambovit was
ready and i realized there are network
level problems so i started
writing my own wallet uh to fix
them for and tumblebee to be ready
to so people can can use it without
ruining their privacy in
in the network level so anthony
was ready and
and then i went to work at
stratis which is an odd coin
uh but they run at timberweet
for their altcoin and for bitcoin and i
was
working on that for a while and that was
called breeze wallet
and to be honest i'm not exactly sure
what happened with breezvalet because a
lot of development effort went into that
and and if i think back
this should have worked out it should
have been a working product
but it wasn't
so so i'm not sure anyway i realized
that i can
do the same what i can do to be time of
it with coin joints
and that's how wasabi came to existence
but one caveat there is that
what we were working on with antambrevit
is tumblr beats tumblr mode
and not the payment hub mode so
no one ever tried to implement the
payment
hub mode which is
which is a very interesting thing it's
what were the problems with that the
problems with that were
that it was unidirectional right you
could send the money
or receive the money you cannot send and
receive money
or it needed equal it needed equal
amount denominations
which makes the user experience a bad
and and it took a lot of
transactions compared to
um not sure the payment of mo now that
design took a lot of transactions
so so anyhow you need directional and
still need additional amounts so
that made made the user experience of
the payment formula
very good and i believe some people
were also working on improving
tumblebeat later on
but but uh but in ways that would
require bitcoin to change so
they really pay more to attend attention
to that
[Music]
so that's the story of tom of it
what do you guys think
any any more insights stories or should
you
want to centralize mixers
all right centralized mixers
now that's an interesting topic too
maybe i have a question she mean simin
did you come across implementations of
not mixing websites but implementations
of the
the research mixed coin blind coin lock
mix of school row
did those things get used i i never
found such a thing but it might
actually uh i didn't find uh
implementation for them
uh they were only scientific papers
uh proposed in um
mixed one and blindfold actually in fc
and they just a scientific paper
at least i couldn't find the mixing
website
who applied those techniques
yeah that was the same experience for me
too
um maybe one interesting thing is
blind queen was operating with xiaomi
and blind signatures
uh if i remember well and
you know it it was a paper in maybe 2016
something like that and at that point
they were so close to coming up with
chummy and co enjoying
which would have
the thing with behind coin if i remember
correctly and
discord me uh that it it provided
accountability so if the servers tears
then
people would know something like that am
i am i correcting that
yeah for blind coin and big fine
the server is the mixer is accountable
actually by providing a warranty
so so they were so close to like just
applying blind signatures to coin joints
which is
chummy and coins are in that i was just
surprised that they didn't at 2016
they should add
all right and
so let's move on to the largest
topic we have which
is the coinjoin based
techniques
nothing much with your mind
giving us a history lesson and coinjoins
just how things came together um
if i understand your question uh you
mean
uh to provide some insights about the
providing better point job
uh yes uh i i said nothing much nothing
much is
uh is a name in in this chat so
he's a real person so i was asking him
but
if you can then i would i would have to
give you your perspective too
actually doing this part um this
research
and then i
find some of the implementation in the
in practice
and for those uh coin join and page one
were commonly used by wallets actually
and the dumpling which was also proposed
by you
uh showed that uh there are lots of coin
joint transaction
from actually from since 2018
where we have uh two new wallets
wasabi and samurai and then
uh i really i was really interested in
the usability of those coin journalists
to see
if the users
could use them and
i try to walk through with my
colleague actually was valley
for those wallets uh john market wasabi
and
also samurai to
perform a user study and
before that we walked through over them
and we found some difficulties really
in performing conjoined transaction with
some of the wallets
and although
to be honestly speaking uh wasabi was
easier to install and to perform
conjoined transactions
[Music]
one of the main problem was the um
the fixed denomination by uh wasabi and
samurai
while a joint market didn't have this
limitation
and just from wasabi i was thinking uh
if the wallet could provide
uh more pools to be entered rather than
a fixed denomination
and for mixing it would be really better
for users especially when
they have a large amount of coins and
in wasabi there is a specific
pool with a small amount and then
they will receive lots of small
coins um i guess
from the usability perspective
it's it's very difficult for the users
uh to
to have too many small coins actually
and it was one of the insights that can
be
improved by providing some more pools in
the
wallet if if it can be actually
actually yes we
so we created the
so we we are working on on the next
mixing technology which
which is which is almost ready at this
point
is it fair to say guys
yes
[Music]
so and and during that research
we created a simulation
which was not published it's it's public
but wasn't like published or made a big
deal out of it
but what the simulation did is took
their current wasabi coin joint
inputs those has never participated in a
mix
so and created
a text file out of this and then
created a bunch of different kind of
coin joints and also created analysis of
these coinjoins
so what we get is
um simulation of
of us writing a bunch of intuitive
algorithms
and different denomination schemes
different
tools different so
i'm going to comparing a bunch of
different kinds of
coin joints how we could could do do
this
and and we came to the conclusion there
that
yes who's indeed
increased the efficiency of the mixes
so so that's that's the one point in my
opinion
that's suggestion
and maybe another question uh for
the transactions in wabi-sabi
[Music]
does it make it a more expensive
in comparison with current
implementation of wasabi then they
should
provide more transactions
um so it's the opposite it
actually makes it orders of multitudes
cheaper the idea
there what is published in the paper is
it's
not published the amount organization
but what is published in the paper is to
how to create
amounts in any phase
right so with blank signatures we can
only create standard
outputs standard denomination outputs
and only those can be considered uh
trust less so only those gain anonymity
and that's why you have to do a bunch of
coin joints because
you have to create those standard
denominations now with bobby savvy
arbitrary ones and and
again i'm not fully up to date with the
implementation
but in the simulation what
we did is that we came up with a bunch
of denomination
systems powers of one powers of
sorry powers of two powers of three
two times powers of three preferred
value series and
powers of ten we came up with with a
number of denominations
instantly couldn't really like put them
together like how to
how to come up with the idea one but
anyhow so we created with a bunch of
these and then what we did
is we were looking other people's
inputs in the mix and
try to decompose our
input sum in a way that
is probably going to encounter with
other people's input sounds
uh decompositions and in that way
we could create coin joints that
rarely very rarely generated changes
and and so that's that's
how far we get in the research about the
implementation
guys
uh just to clarify by change
you mean uh a coin who which has a
unique amount in this case right
yes okay cool um
yeah so the implementation is uh for
several months we've had the
the crypto in place the purpose of the
crypto is just denial of service
protection
much like the blind signature stuff
um we're able to do coin joins
on rag test right now but like the stuff
that you've been talking about
is not yet uh so specifically um
like the logic of how to decompose um
with a specific goal in mind um
and that goal being like optimizing
privacy
that's not yet done uh we still have
only like a stub
implementation that currently behaves
deterministically
but um like it's it's uh
yeah uh so
the lower level details are you could
say that they're finished
but um like actually applying this
to to provide privacy um
like in in a real world setting uh
that's not
that's not there yet um
yeah hopefully within a few weeks we'll
uh we'll have that sorted as well
[Music]
all right so that's what we are up to
is it a lot to take in
all right let's let's talk a bit about
coin shop
because i have one audition to to this
paper
which is well obviously at the beginning
uh tim rafing
annika kate and pedro murray
sanchez came out with the coins of a
paper which
promised decentralized
way of conducting coin joints it wasn't
fully decentralized but uh but
the server was almost like a bulletin
board at that point
uh would be a correct description of
coinshackle
all right i'm going to go with a yes
and then many that's actually very many
implementations
or many people tried to implement point
shuffle
i remember there was mycelium's
implementation
shufflepath which was
done by dania kravis who is a bitcoin sv
proponent currently which just blocks my
mind
how did it happen but anyhow
let's leave some mystery there and
even the cash cash usually now questions
on the electron
cash bitcoin cash guys were implementing
coin shuffle
at the beginning um not sure what was
the name of that
and and then but bitcoin shuttle plus
plus came out very
very early and and actually i
i make a guest here see me see mean
did you have very heavy influence
of of the coins of a plus plus paper
to this paper so was that one that you
you read
more than maybe others
for coin shuffle actually
i just read the paper and where they
provide actually at that time they
provided a newton
technique uh for
being prior
actually for intern preventing internal
uh trade stability between input users
by providing a decryption of
the output addresses
then each of the input users provide
an encryption decryption keys and
decrypt
his own output addresses and send the
sends the output address
which is encrypted by the next party
uh to the next party the next party can
uncreate the message actually then
then adds his own output
and it with the other party and
so on and then the last peer
could actually unencrypt the output
addresses
shuffles them and create control
transaction which also
i remember that one of the papers if i'm
not mistaken coin party told that
the last pier have
the control over the shuffling of the
output addresses
uh and then i tried to find some
implementation for that as you said
shufflepuff and also in
nxt however one of them was
also an awful version
and one of them has removed this
console from the feature list from the
wallet
and for now i i couldn't find
any chrome shuffle wallet to
to test this actually kind of mixing
technique
yes i don't think there is money in
existence the bitcoin cash guys were
using coins of
uh but then they moved on their own
scheme but they figured out which could
actually be applied to bitcoin
but i i think bobby sabby supersedes
that
which is sketch fusion and now cash
fusion is in
production which is having inspired by
by coin sofa but not it's not going to
fall
and and then there was of course coins
of the plus plasmids
but what did it contributed it made
coin james much more efficient much more
secure they given theoretical proofs and
all
kinds of stuff to that and they came up
with this protocol
called dice mix which
was inspired by the descent protocol
which
goes back to the
huge research body of
phononimus communication
right if i remember there are three
categories
one would be broadcaster to cost where
dandelion came out of that
one would be onions which is
which well thor came out of that and
one category would be the
the the mixnets
you know dining cryptographers and
that's where
that's where descent and eventually coin
shuffle comes up
come comes out grows out of concept for
plus plus
is dice mix protocol grows out of so
this
this was my understanding of the history
there
um anything to us
argue it there
okay and here i have uh here i have
something that
you probably did not find in the
research literature because i don't
think it has ever been published
on a on e-printer or or
anywhere it was a github repository
and this was built on coin shafter
plus plus it claimed it made it
decentralized and this was called
byzantine cycle mode by an anonymous
pseudonym assault altar called sound
dance
which uh andre paul astra
and and and the number of
early bitcoin people were excited about
it but
eventually nothing happened with with
byzantine
cycle mode so so that that might be
something to
take a look at a unique interesting
addition
could you please uh repeat the name of
those developers
so byzantine cycle mode
by sound dance
if i remember correctly the pseudonym
and i know that it was published on
bitcoin talk
and github and on bitcoin talk
andrew poastra was very interested in
that
in fact he was the one who who suggested
it to me
back in the days
what did it what did it do guys
literally remember it was manipulating
with some matrixes and
trying to match people together or
something like that
honestly i never quite understood it so
sorry usually i try to fill this in
all right
and then finally we arrive to value
shuffle
which is coin shuffle with confidential
transactions
which is unfortunately not in bitcoin
and that's the end of the
coin suffer research line
it was a very
very well adopted research
actually too bad no final version
that got used but you know the obvious
um tennessee compared to chummy and coin
join
which which i described in
in the zero link specification
and and maxwell described
it that
what was i oh yes this was a
decentralized coordination
with bitcoins of a plus plus even though
i believe um
there was the decentralization wasn't
really
figured out uh properly or
in an implementable way because
because everyone went for the bulletin
board modern
don't worry try to implement coin shaft
for plus plus i believe
okay let's go down and
and i haven't i have a notion to
to coinjoin because you properly
credited maxwell that he
proposed coinjoin um
which which is
i i like to say he popularized it
because
coin joining was around at the time for
for a very long long time and
and the earliest
idea that i i could find
that could be called coinjoin today
was in 2012
uh on bitcoin talk by hashcoin
so i i like to attribute to the
coinjoins to heshcoin personally and
regarding chummy and coin joints that
also wasn't maxwell
who first proposed the idea but uh
but an interesting renamed fellow on
bitcoin talk
called killer storm
he he proposed it i believe in 2013
um what was his real name
nothing much even interacting before
alex mizrahi
[Music]
pronouncing it like you would in hebrew
but
i i don't know if he pronounces the
surname that way
so anyhow i i i that's the earliest
earliest idea that i found about xiaomi
and coin joints which eventually ended
up being implemented in
in wasabi and in strange ways
samurai but let's not
go that far ahead um
all right and
uh something to be added actually
i have another paper uh
which uh investigate the implementation
of coin drawing techniques
in those three wallets and then
in that paper i provided
the techniques that were adopted
for instant maker maker taker uh
for john market and chao myan kong jung
for samurai
and wasabi uh however
and there i explained that they adopted
zero link uh and
i have no idea uh after actually this
discussion
i was thinking that it's better to add
zero link
uh to the category of conjoined here
in this paper actually and and i want to
know
your opinion and
if yes do you think it's better to also
add
a major taker by john market
to this survey paper or it's okay to
have that
in the implementation of going jointex
technique paper
so i believe actually i wanted to
even suggest that i think about joining
market as something
completely completely different so it's
it's it's in its new category
in in coin joins because that maker
thicker model
does things so differently that i
very very often encounter that
i i should really not compare the maker
thicker model in many of the times
with with other coin joining
implementations because
because that's that's so so different
that's
that's so elegant right like hey here is
a bunch of people
they all want to do coin joints uh for
some fee
and you can come and you can make the
coin join yourself
in a way how you want you're the taker
pick some makers and make the coin join
happen
yes that's uh that's uh that's a
completely different model so i would
definitely add that as a category
all right so regarding zero link uh
that i so
so yeah i'm advocating for joining
market now but
i'm not advocating for zeroing because
zero rank
is not a type of coinjoin
however i would advocate for chomi and
coin join
even though there was no really research
paper there
only the zero link specification that
described it
in a way that implementers can implement
it
but xero link is not a type of coinjoin
zero link was the realization that there
are many other
variables where users can ruin their
privacy and they really tried to
bring that together and and said
things about best privacy practices so
xero link is
not a type of coin join it's a privacy
framework for bitcoin wallets
uh but xiaomi and coin join i think yes
that should be a category
uh now what should you reference
um yeah maybe maybe zero link
that's that's probably the first and
maybe the only
only like comprehensive specification of
chomi and coin join yeah
perfect thanks so charming coin time
will be added to the paper
but not fortunately
all right and since we are at this topic
i would like to bring up the
only critique and
i find i believe it's a critique but
maybe because of my biases it's uh it's
probably just a nitpick
of the paper which is there is
a sentence there in the discussion an
analysis bar
part or multiple sentences where you are
comparing
coinjoin implementations or you where
you are giving a few words about
coinjoin implementations
you start with joining market then
wasabi then sunride and blockchain falls
shared coin and
and and and this is what said what is
said there
samurai proposed tool which has
specified
pools where the users can join to mix
their coin with other participants
and create coin joint transactions
so this is correct
and then you go on to say shared coin
which was a coin joint service by
blockchain info
in which blockchain if was able to find
the inputs and
outputs relationships
and this is also correct so
here is two sentence those are both
correct so what's my problem with this
my problem with this is that
you know if you're talking about
blockchain infos flaw
share blockchain enforcement that it is
able to link
the coins the input output relationships
together
then uh you i believe you have to
mention that samurai is also able to
find the relationship because
by default they collect their
users xbox which is an instant download
musician
right it doesn't matter how much you mix
if you have the xbox then
you can find the input output
relationships and
and the counter argument to this is that
use some drive with a full node which
would not expose the input output
relationship
which would not expose the xbox
but on the other hand you are still
mixing with people whose
xbox are exposed because that's
the default that's the light wallet mode
that's the mode where you don't have to
keep 300gb gigabytes of
data on your computer so
even if you're using a full node then
you are also the anonymized by
exclusion because if your input and
output
is the only thing that is on the
anonymized
with the xbox then well
you already anonymized by exclusion so
that's it's a critique i have
what do you guys think
yeah i think you're correct like it's
highly unlikely that like the majority
of
whirlpool users would be running their
own nodes
so anyhow um
all right do you guys
have other topics regarding coinjoin
implementations
uh um i'm getting tired of
of hearing my stuff but i will still
have a good story for patreon later on
can you hear me sorry yep
well no but i would like to know
um because
we can see that coin joints
are probably the most the most
used uh technology for
mixing and that's clearly because i mean
the
the same paper expressed this
very clearly that is because it's
probably the most
cheaper alternative and also in the
number of transactions is the only one
that
is requires only one transaction
right so because it's a color
collaborative
transaction but
uh i would like to
to know from simin
if she shares these
uh no no no as a conclusion but also as
a
as um
[Music]
how about the viability of the the the
others
uh alternatives that are not conjoined
for example
coin swaps um
in in in the sense of the cost
also of course i mean uh
also in the in the impact in the global
um uh anonymity that they provide
because for example just to to explain
myself a bit better
we can see that for example in the in
this
summary in this figure what
all are all the
all the techniques are evaluated we have
something like for example
pay join that says anonymity set
large for example right and coin join
anonymity set
small so
how first
what does it mean that anonymity set is
large
for pay joint and small for
coin joint is this because it was
evaluated in a global
context i mean no locally in the sense
of
each transaction in particular and
again in in the from the point of view
of
the reality the real world um
what's the what
does she think is probably the
the the way to to follow
if it is conjoined the
the most realistic solution
uh actually for for the thing that you
talked about
the the anonymity set i would say that
uh first i tried to
provide it was really it was quite tough
to compare them over in
this criteria actually i just try to
to explain what what it means and uh
first i try to provide something
some fears and some numbers for them but
[Music]
actually i couldn't for coin drawing and
just
i mentioned the problem is finding uh
too many people and
most of the transactions are confined by
the transaction size and
also finding too many people uh
to jointly create a transaction uh would
be
not easy and um in the explanation
i just told that uh as commercial file
and
provide some better uh
solutions for f part in finding the
participants
it could be
actually a medium-sized anonymity set
as they uh in their paper and they
provided
price and i i guess if i'm not mistaken
50 parties you can for coin shuffle plus
plus
and for paging patreon yes
this anonymity set in from the global
view
as you are
hidden uh from all the transactions but
for
conjoined base transactions with equal
based
month uh you need to have uh
more input users to be
the end to be actually to have a large
and
larger anonymity and it was my
uh
definition for comparing those
techniques
and another thing that you told about uh
the price and yes this one would be
really this
transaction fee and number of
transaction
would have uh uh would be a
really really important things in
in the adoption of mixing techniques for
instance
all the coins coin swipe techniques
needs
at least uh four transactions
and for coin join base uh
the mixing can be done uh in just one
transaction uh if the
coinjoin uh if only we
actually accept the coin join
uh as was proposed by
uh conscious by by
excuse me by value shuffle or
by a joint market for
the other implementation they provided
uh
first to mix the coin by coin join
receive it in your
own address and then forward these
mixed coins to your desired address and
even in this case we have a two
transaction
for one round mixing but for other
contract atomic swap actually techniques
we
need at least a four transaction and i
guess
this one would be
a benefit of all the coin drawing base
transactions
thank you
so may i ask uh you mentioned at one
point
that you are working on another paper
which you mind talking about that or is
it too early
yes for that paper
we we installed
all the conjunct wallets and then define
[Music]
some tasks including
installing the valid generating the
wallet and then
funding the wallet performing the
coinjoin transaction
and the last steps is
uh sending this coin joint transaction
to the destination address
and then we worked we had a walk through
over those three wallets uh
to perform control transaction
and in this walkthrough we compare
those wallets in terms of some usability
criteria
and fundamental design criteria
for instance for
mapping if mapping errors
and also the usability criteria
like ease of use and
in this walkthrough we just
[Music]
perform the task step by step
and then if we found some
some problems or some issues or
some errors we just
documented those problems
and also suggest some solutions for
those um
problems and then
for the next paper actually it was just
worked ruled by
two experts for the next
step we would like to do a user study
and ask users uh both technical
and non-technical users to perform
these tasks and then we have
we prepared a questionnaire and a
form where they should answer to some of
the questions
and also provide their satisfication
their time on tasks and
the errors that they received or any
difficulties to
perform the task and we don't
with that user study we can provide uh
problems maybe that you
users may encounter in performing
conjoined with those walls
well that that's interesting because now
we are working on a new version
right and the our focus was
precisely on improving the usability of
our wallet
and making and removing all the painful
points
and make it as easy as possible i think
whatsapp wallet 2 will be
absolutely different and much much
better in usability that was a wallet
one
and the coinjoin part will be
in fact uh transparent from the user's
point of view i mean the user will need
to do
absolutely nothing to to participate in
a coin join it will be done
in background uh and and that's
all so it's i think it's in that aspect
will be
really hard to to
to improve further further because there
is no
it is impossible to make it easier right
uh
but i don't know if we can
have wasabi wallet too ready
on time i don't know what's your your
time your schedule
anyway uh the the the first part all the
send receive parties is
it's almost ready it's 99
ready except the coin joint integration
that is not
it is not done yet
and uh do you have any
estimation of time very
where we can see wasabi too
we have a plan and we estimate that
around 10 weeks
we can have a preview an internal
preview but of course we can
share it with you too anyway everything
is
in github you can just clone the
repository
and get the the latest version but
the the one that will um
have everything let's say in a
alpha version or preview version um
it's it will be done we hope to to have
it done in
around 10 weeks from now if
i'm not mistaken
so yes it would be a really bad time to
do
they use their study for wasabi one
and we didn't know that
well i mean it's it's certainly very
interesting because
because what we do right now is
try to find flaws in the current wasabi
user experience and
do those things differently in a more
seamless way so
if you find the same flaws then oh well
we attempted to fix that but it's pretty
likely that you are going to
find flaws that we didn't even think of
so
that that will still be very interesting
for us
for sure
all right um any questions
to the author about quenching
implementations
or let's move on to pay
join
then pagerank is so
patreon has never been
in a research paper so i was wondering
uh what what did you
you found worthy of
examining
yes actually i first read
a blog post in black history and
from which was pay to end point
and then i found master pay
which was uh sent to
like linux foundation i guess and
then i found uh actually i found it
under the name page joined by
gibson in his workbook
and back then i saw that
in 2020 most of the
wallets are implementing this technique
and that's why we added
this technique to to the paper
and we also we also
had a short paper about
unnecessary input effect
in pay joint transactions
which we considered if
if these unnecessary input inputs can
re flag the page on transactions in the
future
and and yes that's that
however i also i remember that
chris belchers and send an email to
my list that it has not
been adopted mostly by users
i have no idea maybe maybe
most of the users are not familiar with
this technique
and um the community should
maybe advertise this technique
the communities is advertising these
techniques this is
possibly the most advertised privacy
technique in bitcoin
precisely precisely be besides
precisely because of how it
came to existence and
you mentioned that it was
it came from block stream which is kind
of correct
so what happened there in 2017
or 18 is that
actually i was personally i think we
already started working on
on wasabi the the current version of
wasabi and i think lucas was was around
at the time
and and uh there
is a guy called groupers
on twitter and he's working for black
stream
and he brought together
in london a number of
number of people for coinjoining
workshop
that's that was the name and
you know it was that so there was
fro the koi for coin plus shift
[Music]
market me adam beck was
fully with us you know in a
in a small room in london that
just they didn't do any preparing so
all that happened is that
these very smart people
there were more right like around 10 or
15.
uh some of them wants to be anonymous so
that's why i'm
i'm trying to think if i should name
someone's name
but anyhow so some people who worked on
bitcoin privacy before
were brought together into the same room
and
without any any goal
so so what do they do
we start to start to
brainstorm first we go through all the
bitcoin privacy techniques uh
the things that you wrote in your paper
up until 2017 or 18
and then started to to come up with
ideas what should we do
and it was a seven day workshop and
on the fifth day i realized
that the idea that we were pursuing had
a
very serious flaw so
we just realized that we were here for
five days and he didn't come up with
anything at all anything not dirty
you know and
and then adam gives on
and i was talking about
going through some more exotic privacy
technologies
and they found
the idea that satoshi nakamoto was doing
in 2019
which is a2ip sorry 2009
2010 people were able to pay
each other to an ip address uh
which we realized that wow that
it's kind of revolutionary too but it
was removed i mean of course because
ip addresses are not very secure to pay
to but
the connection between
two peers is is huge uh let me get back
to this later
but we didn't want to call it pay2ip
because of course this is secure
so you could possibly pay to a domain
name too
or you could pay to uh an onion
onion domain at or network domain
and and so we decided to
in c sharp there is uh there is a class
called end point which encompasses
all these things and so we decided to
call it pay to end point
and you know this was about
building up a secure connection between
two machines and if you do that
you have a second communication channel
that you can do a bunch of things
uh this is patreon point for example you
can
you can do just simple chat messaging
anonymous chat messaging through
audience or
you can facilitate marriage
avoidance right i think vitaly came
out with a concept or wrote it in a in a
in an early article of him that merchant
boy dances when
you ask multiple addresses from the
server
from from the receiver and then you
split
the money that you're sending so you
could do
that or what else you could do oh we
could decoy
joints we could do these strains
they're gonna graphic coin joints those
look like a payment but to have much
more
interpretations and
well that's later on being called
pay join so that's
what pay join is about making
transactions
making coin joins those are not known to
be
coin joints and that controls blockchain
analysis
now why i
you you had a point there that it did
not get adopted even the wallets
implemented it and
and i have a very specific critique to
that which is
at the time they were trying to
figure out how to do this with bitcoin
urls
uh you know bp 21 urls an extension of
bitcoin url and you know my problem with
that was that that's not
how people use bitcoin uh
they are using
those are merchant scenarios merchant
when you're you buy something from a
website that's
that's when you use bitcoin url all
right so we can encode bitcoin urls into
qr codes
so at least the qr code usage is
satisfied but the main usage of bitcoin
which is
you know uh copy testing addresses
that that
that's not satisfied with
with the big 21 urls uh
because you can't teach it's really hard
to teach the user to
hey even just uh segment bitcoin address
was a
huge mess
in the ui because wallets couldn't stand
to that and
then all kinds of support requests were
coming
so so making the user
use bitcoin urs they don't understand
they
barely even understand to give each
other bitcoin addresses
uh so so i believe that's the order of
the adoption and
if we if
that the current attempts
are pointed toward using bitcoin urls
and
as time passing um i'm getting more
i'm still not very positive on that
approach but
i'm much more positive than i used to be
so maybe that could work uh who knows
we'll see so so the current
attempt buster pay right that was the
first one
and then uh
vip something something
big number uh was by nicola d'oriel
and mostly nicoladore it was another
implementation and of course the joint
market guys were
doing their own implementation then went
on to bitcoin
you are uh of course wasabi is
supporting the sanding part of it
and so maybe it can work
uh who knows but i believe the
the interesting thing would be a pay to
end points
hopefully and i really hope because this
is gonna happen eventually
some kind of uh simplification of
bitcoin wallets will happen
which is we may replace the addresses
with the domain name or
or something but hopefully it will
happen in a
in an anonymous and secure way and
pay to onion would be would be i think
an idea
way to do secure communication because
if you have that then back
you can do the pay joints and
one and and know
the user is doesn't have to notice that
he's even doing
pay joints uh doesn't have to get
familiar with multiple things because if
paid to onion like system
comes alive that would be
that would would make the and it will
that would make the user an option much
easier
all right is that all about
pay to endpoint pay join
then maybe as a closing
session we could have a few questions
stood out or
what do you guys think
i would like to make a comment about way
to
to end point i don't know if if it's
okay or
we could do it after this session is
the same for me go on
well first of all that um
let's start with a pay to ip right
i think the name pay2 it was known as
pay2ip but in fact
the name is quite misleading because it
should be called something like
paid to node because you cannot pay to
any ib the idea was to
pay to one of the nodes that you were
connected
to i mean your node was connected too
and the problem basically is not the ip
the problem is that there are no way to
authenticate the
the pie so for example if
i'm running my node and you're running
your node that you
give me your ip address i i cannot make
sure
i'm paying to your node because
basically the connection is not
authenticated
um so basically all they pay to end
point and pay to ip
or paid to whatever is basically the the
problem is okay
i authenticate the the
the other the other end right that's why
for example
pay to onion could be good because
basically we are sure that we are
connecting to the
to the right um peer let's say
um but
well that's the first thing and the
second one is that
uh now
or right now we are still working with
these
um
bitcoin addresses right that
are okay for normal users probably
because we
we we can expect users are not all the
time online
by a patient for example
it's the idea is like okay this is good
for merchants
right but merchants are all the time
online
right so why to
why to use these
when we can use something more
um how to say
i mean there are there are other ways to
authenticate the users and know only by
a a
a dns or um
and on an onion address i mean
if we can identify some somehow sorry
authenticate
in some way the the the other end
well all the problems are are
ourselves i think probably i i'm missing
something but
i think the problem is basically
authentication
that's all
and being being online receiver
yeah oh yes yes of course yes
i i completely agree
so in conclusion pay joints are
are probably going to have a much better
chance
you know everyone is online world in the
future so
even if it doesn't happen in the next
five years there it is going to happen
in the next 10 years because everyone
i believe everyone is going to be online
all the time
in 10 years so
so don't have to be impatient about it
yes but what i mean is that the fallback
mechanism to pay to the address
in case you cannot connect with the with
the server with the receiver
that's something that is okay now but i
think in the future that will be no
necessary so if you can remove that
that would be pretty awesome right
because you don't need
i mean you can i mean bitcoin addresses
are
uh are not good i think pro
is are not use uh good for for usability
the same happens with vip21 that
those url addresses all that is is
confusing
and really confusing for for normal
people
all right looks like we just converge
any other comment or question
actually there are there are some points
in this talk that were really perfect
and i would add them
to the paper if it's okay from your side
now we would we would be happy to
maybe maybe then we should say a few
words about
ourselves uh just just don't you know
who you're talking with uh
i suppose except me because
you probably know my work at this point
but let's go through the course
who are you
sorry sorry how do you justify your
wretched existence
sorry i i i was uh i'm sorry i i was
uh answering uh a question from my wife
in another chat
so i'm sorry can you repeat the question
oh we were talking about that maybe we
should say a few words about ourselves
uh
so shimmy knows who she was talking to
today oh okay
yes perfect well um i'm lucas
i'm a wasabi developer uh that
started contributing with um
wasabi wallet from from the beginning
i mean after we bring or after
adam rename the magical crypto what no
the height and wallet 2 magical crypto
wallet
i joined to him
so it i started working with him in the
magical crypto wallet that
then was renamed as a wasabi wallet
and basically
that's all i'm now working with nothing
much
um and adam and others
to implement the huawei savvy protocol
um what else well i think that's
that's enough
thank you lucas nothing much
thanks
i think i started harassing
adam around 2000
maybe early 2018 or something um
and uh yeah i just had many opinions
about
uh wasabi and uh
eventually uh got involved with
the project and uh so now
we're working on the the wabi-sabi stuff
thank you ruffa
uh hey hi um i'm basically just a
bitcoin pleb
trying to learn uh as much as possible
about
all these like bitcoin privacy
techniques and
yeah really interested to like
listen to this discussion
all right by a psycho are you with us
yep and i'm also just a
blab and just interested about
bitcoin and privacy things and
okay we have btc fud here
oh i'm gonna also plead the club
all right i should have mentioned that
you guys don't have to
give an introduction if you don't want
to want to stay
more super nameless okay so
so yes we we would be we are very happy
that
we succeeded to provide you some
insights of how things are
coming together adam gives an increased
bachelor
maybe also very good to
to talk to because they they know that
the teacher
too
all right questions
to the author
i was actually just wondering like uh
what got you
interested about like privacy stuff
overall
actually doing this research
when i'm talking with normal users
the first question from them is when
they they
ask me what's your teaser about and
i tell them i'm working on blockchain
privacy
and the first thing from the normal
wizard is
it isn't the blockchain is
private why do you work on privacy
the blockchain is private and uh
this shows that most of the normal users
even
um even don't know that
there are some uh privacy issues in the
blockchain
and uh for me it's it's quite
it's quite interesting that uh you also
need uh
some some actually some solutions to
uh to provide awareness for the users
in this community and um
this makes me really really
eager to work on this
[Music]
area actually
yeah i'm like honestly impressed about
the research you've done
like there was so many more
implementations that i
didn't even know about and yeah really
great too
that you made this report thanks
yes but by the way i i i
you know i i i agree because you know
this work it's pretty impressive because
it summarized many of the the research
that we are uh have done before but
also there are a lot of technologies
that you have
investigated that we didn't or at least
i didn't know about that so i
have harm work to do so thank you
thank you very much for that
and also thank you for the opportunity
to present the paper and have your
insights about the paper
all right
are you holding holding there
would you would you like to leave
already do you have to leave or
or can we continue the questions
for me it's okay if there is any
all right then what else do you guys
have
i just wanted to mention that yeah like
whenever you
or if you feel like it's yeah there's
probably
a lot of things to improve in bitcoin
privacy and
yeah like many projects will be really
happy about these kind of like
overall reports comments contributions
all of that
okay we are running out of questions
but not out of topics
so i would like to propose
that we continue with something that
i
i i this afternoon i come up with a
theory of privacy and it's pretty
complex
so i would like to share that with you
guys
but yeah the last
opportunity to ask questions from the
author
okay so would you like to
talk about privacy in a
very abstract sense
try to define it and figure out what the
hell it is
let's go all right so
what is privacy
how would you define privacy what
definitions do you know
about privacy
i like the definition of like you
having the possibility to selectively
reveal
yourself or parts of yourself
but that's a pretty big one
so the i believe the most commonly used
definition for privacy
is it's just used as a word
like it would be meaning secrecy or
anonymity
but the formal definition that you just
mentioned
goes further than that and and we should
mention that there is a legal definition
which was defined
very early the right to be let alone but
let's let alone the law
let's let's go with the
the formal definition which is your
ability to selectively reveal yourself
to the world
what what's what does this mean
why why is it different from secrecy
all right so it is different because
this is not the state of
being this is the
ability
to choose the ability to
choose your boundaries or
as i came to a definition of privacy
as the ability to define
and enforce our boundaries
privacy is an ability to define and
enforce
our boundaries do you guys
think that makes sense
actually uh i agree and
i remember when
google provided
its social network that they also had a
similar definition for the privacy and
it was
uh defined by circles
you had lots of circles and with closure
circles uh
you you could put your closer friends
and i guess uh it's it's com
completely true also in our lives as we
have some circles
as you said boundaries and in those
circles and in those boundaries
which at the center of that and we are
actually and uh
in these boundaries we can share the
information
if the if a friend or if someone
is in our closer the
boundary then maybe they
they know more about our information and
if they are
far from us
they know less
that is certainly something i'm going to
geek on
uh that's for sure thank you that's
that's
actually yeah it was very insightful and
relevant
okay so privacy the ability to define
and enforce their boundaries
uh anyone thinks that's not a fair
definition for privacy
isn't that i i want to prove to you that
this is the essence but
but do you have some entities
do you think intuitively that that might
not be right
okay so now
the next thing what i want to do
is to figure out and and this is i
didn't do
well because it's hard but figure out
what are the sciences
those are studying
privacy the ability to define and
enforce boundaries
what sciences are doing this and
i was able to come up with
a couple of um
dimensions to this
one would be so since privacy is an
ability
then we have to say that
well what kind of ability is it
individual
or an ability of a group or something
else
but this is the distinction i came to
individual ability and
ability of a group and then
there's the define and enforce our
boundaries
so then
the question naturally comes that
what what are
how would you say our boundaries what
what would be the
largest
largest the most the best way to divide
our boundaries into categories
this would be the classic three mind
body and the world
so we want to enforce
our boundaries
of our mind which is what information
we are sharing
to other people
and this is an individual
an individual has a mind
and and then
the body that you know
if you get sexually assaulted
that is an invasion of your privacy
that is
you're failing to enforce or
define your boundaries of your body
so that's in that's another diamonds in
there
and finally the words which would be
which would be an individual or a group
would be able to enforce their
boundaries
to culture
let's say to other families
or to other countries people
or or even our boundaries with
the world and the universe the natural
world
nature right so against culture and
nature that's
that's the word uh so so
we can only see privacy as uh
you know if there would not be
it it would be only me then privacy
privacy will always against other
or always projected against other people
or or or if you
want to bring in this philosophical
direction that
the word is the the natural word is also
something that you want to
define and enforce your boundaries
it doesn't really feel right to say
that we have privacy against the world
but
if we we talk about this
definition what i came up with then then
it would make and
maybe there is something there so it
actually very very corresponds to the
brain to
just just as a interesting story there
that we have the cortex
the limbic system and the reptilian
brain right the cortex
is what thinks what reasons
um in plateau was
calling it the man and freud was calling
it ego
uh basically or that's what corresponds
to it and
there is a limbic system with chair
basically your emotions
plateau was calling it the lion freud
was calling it the super ego
and the reptilian brain which is
your your body in
in this privacy privacy
metaphor the cortex would be the mind of
course
the
the reptilian brain
which is like you're hungry and this
kind of things
that would be your body
in plateau the reptilian was the monster
and
freud that's the freudian eat so
suniyah doesn't matter just interesting
thing
the point is that
the mind what
so we we can come up with
two with sciences here
that what is the science that
is examining on how to describe the mind
but what's dealing with the mind what is
that science
that describing not applying
what science is trying to
examine the mind guys
am i muted nope uh i don't know maybe
some kind of psychology study
uh-huh psychology is one of them yes
[Music]
i'm sorry assuming i can't hear you
social sciences
social sciences huh
okay so
i came to the conclusion that there are
multiple sciences those are studying in
the mind uh social sciences
in the like anthropology you know that's
looking at culture and these kind of
things that they
they are saying that that's the that's
the thing what they are studying the
mind
or something like that and
psychology right that's studying the
mind on another level
uh there is of course neuroscience
that's studying
the brain itself and ultimately the mind
there is linguistics because we
are communicating our minds
to each other with our language so
so they say that's another thing that's
that's uh studying the mind and finally
there is artificial intelligence
she's trying to figure out how to create
a
mind like information processing system
so so that's that's another thing and
these all of these
are being integrated
or trying to be integrated into one
science
or trying to have cross-disciplinary
conclusions between them and that
science is called cognitive science
so that's why cognitive science is for
example called the multidisciplinary
discipline because there are
many disciplines that it is
trying to dive into and the only thing
come on in
those is that all of these disciplines
or they are choosing
from all of these disciplines the parts
those are
studying the mind
so i would say cognitive science
tries to define define the mind
and cognitive science is trying to
figure out what's our meaning what we
should do
and getting into enlightenment
those kind of stuff or at least
one guy that i was watching on youtube
was going into
uh and he's a cognitive scientist so
anyhow the point is that
that's what describes the mind okay
what science is
trying to enforce
the boundaries of the mind trying to
enforce
safe heat information
safety financially information
uh because you know tools are
we are told using creatures and
those are basically become part of our
body and
you know our financial situation is
basically a tool so so what we are doing
with our finances that
that's part of ourselves that's an
extension of ourselves
uh so so what science is trying to
enforce
boundaries of information and
the information like things like
bitcoins
safekeeping private keys
yeah it was just i don't know how to
correctly form it but
you're like compressing all kind of
information or like yeah whenever you're
kind of like
creating password or passwords or
hashing
you know like that's that's kind of like
compressing certain
amounts of like data into like
behind a lock but something that it's
still
even easier for you maybe to remember or
decrypt when needed but i'm not sure if
that's
like what exactly that what you meant
guys ideas
what science is trying to enforce
apply that the content of our minds
doesn't get to other parties
or or well you know
and forcing is not only hiding but
sorry um so revealing yourself to the
world so
basically enforcing is not only hiding
the information but also
revealing or proving the information
right it could even divide that into two
categories
so so what what is the science that
does it that tries to
hit the privacy
from other other people or other groups
i mean it's not like science or at least
not that i would
know uh what kind of scientist science
it is but
kind of like these research wherever you
are looking into
for example uh you know these like tails
uh certain actions that make it
really clear that you are lying for
example
so these kind of researchers might be
kind of like
wanting to you for to know whenever you
are giving out an information that you
actually wouldn't want to give out
or do you mean like cryptography
or something that's exactly what i mean
but i'm not very happy with that because
it
seems like it's such a it's a sub
category of mathematics
yet i cannot think of any other science
that would be
dealing with with
constraining information in dealing in
an adverse area settings and
it can prove things and it can
hide things that
that's what cryptography is about
maybe a more philosophical part of
cryptography where
where the math is not that heavy but
rather the
cryptographic thinkings the
cryptographic patterns
that those can be you know applied in
real-world situations completely offline
too
right it's game theory
cryptography that's my best best guess
but yeah any anyone has any
any better one because i don't
i don't have any anything better in mind
but that's an interesting
point
okay so the next one is also something
that i
did not i may have found the right one
but i'm not 100 sure about which is
what's the fact so again privacy is the
ability to define
and enforce your boundaries of the word
your boundaries so and now
we move on to the body level
we went through the mind and now we move
on to the body
so what what is the thing that
tries to
define or enforce
boundaries in the world like what
what's in the body level so what
describes the body what is dealing with
the body
i would say like like self-defense tools
i thought about that too
uh you know yeah self-defense and
martial
arts and and things like this
uh but then i generalized so this is the
enforcement
under the enforcement right but then i
generalized into
you know
the whole health industry
the fitness industry
is basically trying to
enforce your
oh you know pick this drug
right that's an invasion of your privacy
but in in the level of your body
so they are trying to help you what
substance is to introduce to your body
and that kind of the enforcement part
that
now you have the tools to take this drug
and
make your life better and by drug i
i don't i might mean
party drugs but more like a medicine
or creatine or multivitamin or
vitamin d what have you and
and the fitness part is like
possibly all the sports that just makes
you your body work better in the world
is
is just a better way for you to
to use your body in the verse so that
it's kind of
i think you can generalize to the whole
heart industry
that is set out to make your body
work better and
and special mention to martial arts when
your
your privacy is being invaded
by like in a very not
good situation like a sexual assault
something like that
so that's that's my thinking on the
enforcement part
making yourself your body work better
is basically your body operate better in
the world
um okay so this
is also something i'm not hundred
percent satisfied with
for the defining i found biology
and all the some biology sciences
that's a big big big thing there but
that's
yeah what do you guys think i think
biology is what
describes the body figures out what your
boundaries should be
to what kind of substances you're
introducing to your body
uh what kind of i don't know movements
you need to take
freeze or fly or all this kind of stuff
uh not not sure about these things
but yeah so the fitness industry and
martial arts and
that is probably the enforcement of
of conducting your body in the world and
being able to define your boundaries
yeah and overall i i think like all of
these physical things like just
for example doors or curtains or things
like that they are kind of like
yeah protection for your like physical
privacy
we'll put that into birth category
or
yeah maybe maybe it should come here
yeah first of all
i don't know closing is
it's a privacy tool right you choose
your clothes
you choose what you're revealing of your
body
and what you don't so so
well you can't call closing science but
um yeah there is a there's something
there
curtains and
yeah i mean like yeah somebody probably
did some research on why not to build
your house walls on glass and i think
even though it's not maybe like the most
important part i think privacy
is also one of the things that they had
to consider
and with like many yeah many of these
things
like yeah with clothes and whatever
they kind of like do have to think about
the privacy side and what do people
reveal
all right so let's go to the last and
most abstract
category which arguably shouldn't even
be here
but maybe it should be here
let's see so if privacy is the ability
to define it then force
our boundaries then
think about boundary
as the world
and culture
so not nature
i'm not sure we should go that far but
to sculpture
so boundaries is
other people other groups of people
your group of people so it's a group
ability not an individual ability at
this
point so your groups of people
uh try to enforce boundaries against
other
groups of people
now what
what's what is the science that defines
and what is the science that enforces
these boundaries let's
start with the define what science
defines
tries to understand the world
in a sense in terms of
groups of people's relationship
how they gonna behave to each other
things like that
that's where i arrive to economics
because i think that's what
is trying to capture the
the significant things
um in terms of groups of people
interacting or people being able to
live with each other
and define their own boundaries and
don't have to all the time fight
on the boundaries yeah if you think
about that
that's what we do people we just fight
on the boundaries because we can never
come to consonants on
any lines we write them in the sand
sonia
economics is what i came to that's
trying to
define the
boundaries between people
groups of people what
what is that does that make sense
yeah i think it does like that was also
the first thing that came to my mind
and also like if yeah economics and
like philosophy
some of them at least talk about like
individualism
and yeah even like how to
there's a lot of like researches also
about like how to protect your
uh yeah your individualism and
how to actually make or like enforce
these boundaries against
other peoples and yeah about like
your own uh autonomy
and respecting others
how about enforcement
what is what are the
sciences those can
can benefit from economics the most
maybe those ones those make
a difference in the world
and that's probably
politics and technology
and
and you know i i don't know if this is
science but the creation of
ideas i don't know if that makes sense
never mind
so politics and technology that's what i
come to
again i'm not really happy with this
but since listen upon
for now
and you know philosophy
is what we are doing right now because
you know philosophy is science of
integration philosophy is integrating
sciences together so
we are coming up with the new science
the new science of
privacy this is the first step
you know integrating sciences together
just to try to find out what privacy is
but you know i believe if a person who
who gets his privacy right on the level
of the mind
body and the world and that kind of
unifies this being and
not and not being that anxious anymore
because he knows exactly what he wants
he knows exactly
um how to
how to define these process these
levels and where to enforce
and where to reveal their
where to hide and where to reveal their
the things that they want to or don't
want to
reveal or hide so
well that's philosophy
the way of the privacy
let's get the
also like i'm not sure if this is uh
like directly connected
uh like to the topic but in my opinion
like about
creating these boundaries or like
it wasn't like research per se but
in my opinion like one of the most
insightful
uh like literature that i've
seen or read about like these kind of
making boundaries between like groups of
people
i think it was the second realm
book like there was a lot of like really
interesting and deep
like strategical things about
how to preserve and defend your own
uh yourself or your group's privacy
and all kind of like small psychology
things about like
signs and yeah different
ways to communicate with one another
and stuff like that
so would you say that
but what it's doing is the offline
equivalent of cryptography
um not maybe exactly it was mainly
in my opinion like um
like if you want to be left alone
type of thing
there are certain things that you must
consider
like for example like how visible are
you
to others and you know you kind of do
want to signal for your own
people that's maybe like what you're
doing
and what is going on over here but you
don't want others to know about it so
yeah kind of different kind of like
flags or
um whatever things that
yeah the most of the people may not
understand but you can
kind of communicate in the physical
world to your own people
i mean that sounds like the offline
version of cryptography as far as i
understand cryptography
yeah now that you said it yeah kind of
yeah i had a lot of ideas back then that
you know are is
a bunch of cryptographic concepts
different things
society generals and all kinds of things
and you know
how often would it be to just
try to come up with reverse scenarios
where this cryptographic concept could
be
useful without computers
i think there's a lot to discover there
like isn't kind of like uh for example
dining cryptographers
are possible to like do
in a physical world right
uh-huh exactly dining crypto reverse
it's a
it's a good one
all right guys that's
that's all about my crazy new
theory it's in the future or might not
but uh anyhow thank you for hearing me
out
i think you can stop the live stream
what do you say yeah
sure this has been a good discussion
all right then thank you guys for coming
and if you would like to
stay for a non-recorded conversation
then please stay if you would like to
leave then please leave in fact leave
any time you
you would like to don't feel shy about
it
um so
thank you i want one last thing
uh i was just wondering if uh simin
wants to
tell the viewers maybe like where they
can
uh find you or yeah send you a message
if
they have some ideas or yeah where to
just follow your work
actually currently the paper is on
eprint
and my email also
is there and then they can contact me
via my email
all right all right thank you ruffa
i should have definitely did that
anyhow so thank you guys for
for being with us did you enjoy the
episode
it was it was
really like the compression of all the
previous wasabi research cards into
one episode or at least the topics were
there or like that so
i'm not sure if anyone is able
sit through these
really difficult concepts from the
beginning
but if you did then i'm sure you
did enjoy this episode too so
thank you and and stay around for
uh for non-recorded conversation
bye bye bye
bye